SHAFKATH SAYEED CHOUDHURY, FCCA

Address: Flat # D4, Eastern Garden, 2/A Eskaton Garden, Dhaka

Mobile No 1: +8801799445590 Mobile No 2: +8801708491477

e-mail: shafkath79@gmail.com, shafkath791@gmail.com



Career Objective:

I wish to work in such a working environment that poses challenge while offers opportunity to develop my career enriching it with experiences enabling me to maximize the profit of the organization in a sustainable fashion.

Career Summary:

I have more than 11 years of experience that entails Internal Audit, Accounting, Product Management, FMCG operation etc. I have worked in Bangladesh and UK that includes experience of two MNCs (BP & Tesco). I have worked in textile industry where raw material costing was one of my job responsibilities. I look forward to have a career in any wing of business as I believe my innovative nature and quick learning ability equip me to excel in any form of venture with a profit motive.

Special Qualification:

FCCA(UK), SAP (German ERP Software) Implementation & Usage, Advanced Excel, SAGE, Tally, VAT trained, Fluency in English with British accent. MBA (DU), SOP Preparation & Implementation, Enterprise Risk Assessment

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 11.1 Years

1. Assistant General Manager (January 1, 2017 - Continuing)

Crown Cement Group

Company Location: Gulshan 2, Dhaka

Department: Internal Audit **Duties/Responsibilities:**Review of financial statements

Ensuring appropriate accounting treatments are being done in SAP for FICO module

Financial statements are prepared as per relevant IFRS/IAS Ensuring updated and non-asset register maintenance

Risk based internal auditing,

Departmental budgeting and planning,

VAT/AIT compliance during pre-audit of all bills of group

Ensuring appropriate inventory valuation along with regular count planning and execution and adjustments

Reviewing sales incentives with cost benefit analysis

Any other assigned works by management.

2. Deputy Manager (July 1, 2015 - December 31, 2016)

Super Star Group (SSG)

Company Location: Shegunbagicha, Dhaka

Department: Internal Audit **Duties/Responsibilities:**

Review of factory costing, ensuring TDS, VDS are being deducted properly, appropriate accounting treatments are being done in SAP for FICO module, financial statements are prepared as per relevant BFRS/IFRS, fixed asset register is being maintained and updated, customer credit limits are being followed, payments are being received as per SOP, implementing as well as evaluating effectiveness of internal controls, with a risk based audit approach, carrying out internal audit assignments in group owned strategic business units like SS Renewable Energy Ltd , evaluating financial controls as per SOP and recommending further controls wherever necessary, assessing group expenses, special and regular offers of sales department, analyzing costing process and recommending changes wherever needed.

3. Assistant Manager (January 1, 2014 - June 30, 2014)

Liz Fashion (China-Germany-Bangladesh Joint Venture Knit Composite Textile Group)

Company Location : Shafipur, Gazipur Department: Finance & Accounts

Duties/Responsibilities:

Costing of raw materials, Financial reporting for Management with emphasis on material costing, project costing.

4. Assistant Manager (December 2009 - October 2010)

Computer Source Limited

Company Location : Dhanmondi, Dhaka Department: Product Management

Duties/Responsibilities:

Cost Analysis, Variance Analysis, Profit Projection & Budgeting, Product Management, Pricing, Distribution,

5. Articled Student (February 2009 - March 2009)

KPMG Rahman Rahman Hug

Company Location: 9 Mohakhali Com. Area (11th & 12th Floors)

Department: Audit

Duties/Responsibilities:

Assigned Client: Huawei, External Audit

6. Administration & Internal Audit (July 2008 - January 2009)

East West University

Company Location: 43 Mohakhali C/A,Dhaka Department: Administration & Internal Audit

Duties/Responsibilities:

Internal Audit, Tender Analysis & Processing, Operational Expense Analysis & Reporting

7. Officer, Cash & Inventory Management (January 2006 - October 2006)

Tesco

Company Location: 125 Sutton RD Erdington, Birmingham United Kingdom

Department: General Sales **Duties/Responsibilities:**

Inventory Management, Cash Handling, Delivery reception & necessary paperworks, Refunds, Customer Service

8. Officer, Cash & Inventory Management (January 2005 - December 2005)

BP Safeway

Company Location: Staple Tye, Great Parndon Harlow, Essex CM18 7BH

Department: General Sales **Duties/Responsibilities:**

Inventory Management, Cash Handling, Delivery reception & necessary paper works, Refunds, Customer Service

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pass.Year	Duration	Achievement	
Association of Chartered Certified Accountants	Financial Accounting, Cost & Management Accounting	ACCA (UK)	Awarded	2016	3 Years	ACCA (Member)	
МВА	Business Administration	University of Dhaka	CGPA:3.8 out of 4	2008	2 years	GPA 3.80	
Bachelor of Social Sciences	International Relations	University of Dhaka	Second Class	2003	4 Years	7th Position	
HSC	Humanities	Sylhet Cadet College	First Division	1997	2 years	Board Scholarship	
SSC	Science	Sylhet Cadet College	First Division	1995	2 Years	Star Marks(Over 75% Marks)	

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Red Hat Certified Engineer	Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.0	BASE IT Ltd	Bangladesh	Suvastu Chandrashilla Tower, Panthapath, Dhaka	2007	6 Months
Microsoft Certified Professional	Microsoft Windows 2000 Server Configuration	Desktop IT	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2003	6 Months
C /C++ Programming	Programming Language C++ programming & Application	Dhaka University Computer Association	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2000	6 Months

Professional Qualification:

Certification	Institute	Location	From	То
VAT Laws and Regulations Dr. Abdur Rouf (@BDJOBS Center) Kawran B.		Kawran Bazar, Dhaka	October 2016	November 2016
Advanced Interviewer Training	SSG	Dhaka	August 24, 2016	August 24, 2016
SPSS (13)	University of Dhaka	Dhaka	January 1, 2009	April 10, 2009
Tally 9 (Accounting Software)	East West University	Mohakhali, Dhaka	October 1, 2008	December 31, 2008
Computerized Accounting (SAGE)	City & Guilds Certification(UK)	Birmingham, UK September 9, 2004		April 10, 2005
CLAIT Plus Spreadsheet	OCR Certification, UK	UK	September 9, 2004	March 30, 2005

Career and Application Information:

Looking For	:	Top/Mid Level Job
Available For	:	Full Time
Present Salary	:	Tk. 232.000
Expected Salary	:	Tk. 400,000

Extra Curricular Activities:

Creative Writing, Basic Education Promotion, Social Awareness Promoting Programs

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
English	High	High	High
Bengali	High	High	High
French	Medium	Medium	Medium
Arabic	Medium	Low	Low

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Late Abu Sayeed Ahmed Choudhury

Mother's Name : Nurun Nahar Choudhury
Date of Birth : November 4, 1979

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : Flat # D4,Eastern Garden, 2/A Eskaton Garden, Dhaka

Current Location : Dhaka

Reference (s):

Ref	eren	ce:	01
-----	------	-----	----

Name : Md. Shakir Amin Chowdhury

Organization : Dhaka Bank Limited

Designation : Sr. Executive Vice President

Address Biman Bhaban, 100 Motijheel C/A Dhaka

1000

Phone (Off.) : 00880-2-9558704

Phone (Res.) : Mobile :

E-Mail : shakir.chowdhury@dhakabank.com.bd

Relation : Professional

Reference: 02

Dr. Ubaidur Rob, Ph. D. Population Council Country Director

House CES (B), Road No: 118 Gulshan, Dhaka

+880-2-8821227/8826657

urob@popcouncil.org

Professional